Sharang Gupta

Versatile Software Developer

Cloud computing proponent. Evolving into full stack.

+44-7385890562

Salford

in linkedin.com/in/sharanggupta

EDUCATION

MSc in Computer ScienceUniversity of Southampton

09/2020 - 09/2021

First Class Honours(predicted)

BTech in Computer Science

Symbiosis International University 🗷

06/2014 - 05/2018 3.468/4

Diploma in Business Management

Symbiosis Institute of Business Management

06/2017 - 07/2018

First Class Honours

WORK EXPERIENCE

Freelance Web Developer

Thiasil 🗷

01/2020 - 10/2020

Highlights

 Developed a website hosted on an EC2 instance, as a freelance project for Thia Glass Works: https://www.thiasil.com/

Python Developer

Karza Technologies Private Limited

12/2018 - 09/2020

Fin-tech company performing background checks on loan applicants Highlights

- Created over 300 web crawlers, harvesting millions of data points, thus creating end to end data pipelines for consumption
- All the data harvested has been sold directly(Voter IDs) and indirectly(RBI) to the clients, and the company's revenue quadrupled during my tenure

Web Developer

Bombardier Transportation 🗷

08/2018 - 11/2018

Highlights

 Responsible for developing WEB-HMI, a user interface for metro drivers to control the train

Intern

Symantec Corporation 🗷

01/2017 - 06/2017

Highlights

- Developed a new Non-PE files harvester, to gather 1 million files to whitelist, met the target within 3 months itself, and went on to work as a full-fledged software developer for the rest of my tenure
- Developed a new crawler in record time, for a time sensitive project involving a lawsuit threat against Symantec

SKILLS



PROJECTS

Heart Disease Prediction

 Performed exploratory data analysis, algorithm selection and implementation and obtained an F1-score of 95%

Fake News Detection 🗹

 Performed exploratory data analysis, feature generation and algorithm selection on the mediaeval data set of tweets

BlockVote 🛂

 Developed a voting system based on blockchain technology, based on Django. Implemented the cast_vote and check_vote functionality of the project

Parivahan Scraper 🗹

 Developed a web crawler to scrape details of the registered vehicle hosted using Flask on an AWS EC2 instance

Web Profile - Dr Himanshu Agarwal 🗗

 Developed a web profile page for Dr Himanshu Agarwal hosted at https://sitpune.dev/~himanshu.agrawal/ ☑

WheresMyMoney: A Personal Expense Tracker 🗹

 A transaction management application based on Android with a FireBase backend and MaterialDesign UI

Wifi Treasure Hunt: Popular tech-fest game at SIT 🗹

 An android app involving clues being displayed upon arriving within the range of certain wifi hotspots

TEACHING EXPERIENCE

Symbiosis Institute of Technology (03/2017 - 04/2017)

Taught 2nd year MTECH students android app development, in order to leverage sensors of a mobile phone, as a part of their IoT course

CERTIFICATES

Smart India Hackathon 2018 Grand Finale (03/2018)

Developed a solution to calculate trade margins for businesses, under the Ministry of Statistics and Programme Implementation

Six Sigma Black Belt (02/2016)

Certified by MSME of the Government of India

Six Sigma Green Belt (02/2015) 🗗

Certified by MSME of the Government of India

LANGUAGES

English	Hindi
Fluent	Fluent